A Guide to the Lyric Theatre Collection, 1922-2006 (bulk, 1922-1979)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Lyric Theatre Collection, 1922-2006 (bulk, 1922-1979)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2017-034
0.7 Cubic Feet 5 boxes; 1 folder
The Lyric Theatre Collection contains lobby cards, event programs, film flyers, and several film-related newsletters, dating from 1922 to 2006. The majority of the collection consists of lobby cards (1936-1979) and film flyers (undated, but mostly c.1920s-1950s).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The Lyric Theatre Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Materials in the Lyric Theatre Collection were received from a variety of sources prior to 2000.
Scope and Contents
The Lyric Theatre Collection contains lobby cards, event programs, film flyers, and several film-related newsletters, dating from 1922 to 2006. The majority of the collection consists of lobby cards (1936-1979) and film flyers (undated, but mostly c.1920s-1950s). The lobby cards include program schedules, film times/dates, and local advertisements. Programs printed specifically for Lyric Theatre events include information for single-events, as well as pamphlets or flyers advertising a series of events (usually occuring around the same time). The film flyers were mass-produced for movie theater use, but most of the ones in this collection contain a stamp with the name "Lyric" and show dates and/or times.
Arrangement
The Lyric Theatre Collection is arranged in series and subseries by material type. Series I: Lobby Cards, 1936-1979, are in chronological order. Any duplicates of existing cards are located in a separate box at the end of the series.
Series II: Programs and Film Flyers, 1922-2006, is divided into two subseries. Subseries A: Programs, includes flyers, broadsides, and small pamphlets published for Lyric-specific events like film screenings, plays, or local shows. This subseries is organized into two parts: programs for single events and programs for multiple events. Within each section, materials are in chronological order with undated items at the end. Subseries B: Film Flyers are mostly undated (or only contain a month/day). This subseries contains small pamphlets, broadsides, and other ephemera describing individual films (some combination of titles, producers, directors, and/or actors). Many contain a stamp for the Lyric with show dates and/or times. In additions, this subseries includes four oversize film newsletters and flyers. Materials in this subseries are in alphabetical order by film title.
Adjunct Desciptive Data
Related Materials
Special Collections contains a number of resources (books and manuscripts) that relate to the history of the Lyric Theatre.
Files and architectural drawings in Projects #174, #340, #433, #480, #497, #1019, #1497, and #1883, Smithey & Boynton, Architects & Engineers Records, Ms1992-027. Finding aid available online.
Lyric Theatre folder, Historical Photograph Collection, Special Collections. Finding aid available online.
Lyric Theatre folder, Blacksburg Vertical File, Special Collections. Finding aid available online.
Lyric Resource Notebook, compiled by Stephen Michener, 1994. Copy available for use in Special Collections.
The Lyric Theatre: The Heart of Blacksburg, a history written by Lesley Howard, Su Clauson-Wicker, and Cheryl Wood Ruggiero, 2015. Copies available in Special Collections and Newman Library.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Lyric Theatre (Blacksburg, Va.)
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Montgomery County (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South
Genre and Form Terms:
Ephemera
- Series I: Lobby Cards, 1936-1979
  - 1936-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1956 (Box 2)
  - 1957-1979 (Box 3)
  - Duplicates of cards in Boxes 1-3 (Box 4)
- Series II: Programs and Film Flyers, 1922-2006 (bulk, 1920s-1930s)
  - Subseries A: Programs, 1922-2006
    - Lyric Programs (for multiple events), 1923-1928, 2006, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Lyric Programs (for single events), 1922, 1995, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: Film Flyers, n.d., but likely c.1920s-1950s
    - Film Flyers, A-D (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Film Flyers, E-H (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Film Flyers, I-N (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Film Flyers, O-S (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Film Flyers, T-Z (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Oversize Flyers and Newsletters, c.1930s? (Folder 1)